# Thomas C. Hsu

Mobile: (732) 647-5373 | Email: thomaschsu@gmail.com | Holmdel, NJ 07733 Linkedln: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tomchsu/ | Portfolio: https://thomaschsu.github.io/

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/thomaschsu">https://github.com/thomaschsu</a>

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with a focus on the front-end. Proven background in developing user-friendly websites and web applications. Well-versed in various programming languages including JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node, and more. A proactive professional who enjoys systematically testing websites for bugs and debugging errors. Looking forward to applying my knowledge and expertise in web development to a like-minded company to ensure quality user interaction that produces optimal results.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Responsive Web Design, JSON, React
- Magento 1 & 2 E-commerce
- WordPress
- Node.js, Firebase
- Express
- SEO
- MongoDB

- GIT, GitHub
- Bootstrap, Materialize
- APIs, AJAX
- CLI
- Microsoft Office Suite and Adobe Suite
- MySQL
- Heroku

### **APPLICATIONS BUILT**

## MRA International Company Website

- Front-End Developer of a group of three
- Company website that provided the world with information about MRA International
- WordPress, HTML, CSS, Graphics Design

## MRA International Storefront

- Front-End Developer and Catalog manager of a group of three
- Storefront for MRA International that sold computers and electronics
- Created multiple stores for different Universities selling configured HP equipment
- Magento, HTML, CSS, Graphics Design

## **Goodmovies**

- Lead Front-End Developer of a group of three
- Website dedicated to finding movies based on rotten tomatoes ratings
- Ability to save favorite movies into Firebase
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Firebase, APIs, jQuery

## <u>Liri - Node Application</u>

- Node application that uses Twitter, Spotify, and OMDB API to display information depending on what arguments you input
- Implemented in friendly UI. uses Counter
- JavaScript, APIs, Node, Node Modules

### **New York Times - Search**

- Lead Front-End Developer of a group of four
- A page that searches through NYT using gueries and NYT API
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, APIs, jQuery

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## MRA International - Long Branch, NJ

March 2013 - February 2018

## Website Administrator, Web Developer, IT Technician, Inside Sales Representative

- Took a lead role in the production and maintenance of a front-end Magento and WordPress company website.
  Included implementing a PunchOut catalog, systematically testing the website for bugs, and managing the backend Magento catalog.
- Built and managed graphics for the front-end of the website
- Provided client services in massive company project that required imaging thousands of laptops and desktops for Elizabeth school districts within tight time constraints.
- Repaired malfunctioning desktops and laptops and networked with customers in addition to being an inside sales representative.

DuPont - Parlin, NJ

June 2007 - August 2007 | May 2008 - August 2008 | June 2011 - July

2011

## Manufacturing Technician LSE

- Assisted with processing, inspection, and packaging of Cyrel Flexographic plates
- Distributed finished products
- Gained knowledge in patience and hard work

### **EDUCATION**

Rutgers University - New Brunswick, NJ

Full Stack Web Development - Coding Program

Rutgers University - New Brunswick, NJ

School of Arts and Sciences | School of Information Technology and Informatics | Bachelor of Arts

Major: Information Technology and Informatics

Minor: Psychology